# Zach Gulde

# Summary

I like solving both technical and business problems with code and data, sharing knowledge with others, automating the automatable, and a good cup of hot coffee.

\*Note: this resume has been prepared with minimal formatting. Visit https://zgulde.net/ for a prettier version.

### Contact

**\( 210 473 0725** 

github.com/zgulde

San Antonio, TX

zach.gulde@gmail.com

# Skills

Programming Languages Python | JavaScript | Java | HTML | CSS | Clojure | Bash | PHP

**Development**Web Applications | Command Line Tools | Infastructure Automation | Cloud Deployments |
React | Docker | Git | JSON APIs | Object Oriented Programming

Data Web Scraping | Data Wrangling | Data Visualization | R | Applied Statistics | Machine Learning

# Education

Codeup Sep 2015 to Feb 2016 Certificate of Completion in Web Development

**Texas A&M** Sep 2008 to May 2012 BS Anthropology (Incomplete)

Western Governors University Jan 2017 to June 2021 BS Software Development

# Certifications

Java SE 8 OCA Oracle Mar 2017

A+ CompTIA May 2018

Project+ CompTIA Jun 2020

ITIL 4 Foundation PeopleCert Oct 2020

# Experience

Curriculum Developer, Data Science Instructor, Web

Feb 2016 to Present (5

**Codeup** | Development Instructor

| years)

I split my time between teaching, improving Codeup's curriculum, and working on internal tools and infastructure.

- Designed and implemented Codeup's change from teaching PHP to Java and introduction of Data Science.
- Designed, implemented, and maintain a custom LMS, including curriculum versioning and deployment
- Continously update and improve curriculum content for Full-Stack Java and Data Science

Mentor students and manage 4-6 project groups during their 3-week real-world capstone projects

Whiskr | Software Developer | May 2016 to May 2017 (1 year)

- Built out RESTful endpoings for social media influencer tracking into an existing PHP + Laravel application
- Built an automated webscraper with selenium and python to acquire cruise price data

# **Projects**

#### **Codeup Curriculum**

I co-authored Codeup's custom curriculums for both the web development and data science programs. The course takes students from little to no background to enough knowledge to be a practicioner.

#### Cods

Bash scripts that automate the cloud deployment of Java, Python, PHP, or Node web applications and static web sites to one or more virtual private servers.

github.com/zgulde/cods

# **Codeup Tools Application**

Internal Custom Tool for Codeup Instructors and Administrators. PHP, HTML, CSS, and Javascript code integrates curriculum access management, custom quizzes, and student grade management, and student notes.

### **GitHub Activity Tracker**

A tool to keep tabs on Codeup students' GitHub activity. Python code reads from a MySQL database, fetches information from the GitHub JSON API, and updates a Google sheet available to various stakeholders.

#### **Portfolio**

Check out my open source portfolio (https://zgulde.net/portfolio/) for more selected works, or browse through any of the repositories on my GitHub.